He had to find her... he had to find her...
The Searchers is a western film directed by John Ford.
As a Civil War veteran spends years searching for a young niece captured by
Indians, his motivation becomes increasingly questionable.
Ethan Edwards, played by John Wayne.
Martin Pawley, played by Jeffrey Hunter.
Laurie Jorgensen, played by Vera Miles.
Rev. Capt. Samuel Johnston Clayton, played by Ward Bond.
Debbie Edwards, played by Natalie Wood.
Lars Jorgensen, played by John Qualen.
The Searchers is a 1956 American epic Western film
directed by John Ford and written by Frank S.
Nugent, based on the 1954 novel by Alan Le May.
It is set during the Texas–Indian wars, and stars John Wayne as a middle-aged Civil War veteran who, accompanied by
his adopted nephew (Jeffrey Hunter), spends years looking for his abducted niece (Natalie Wood).
It was shot in VistaVision on Eastmancolor negative with
processing and prints by Technicolor.
The film was a critical and commercial success.
Since its release, it has come to be considered a masterpiece and one
of the greatest and most influential films ever made.
It was named the greatest American Western by the American Film Institute in 2008, and it placed 12th
on the same organization's 2007 list of the 100 greatest American movies of all time.
Entertainment Weekly also named it the best Western.
The British Film Institute's Sight and Sound magazine ranked it as the seventh-best film of all time based on a 2012 international survey of film
critics and in 2008, the French magazine Cahiers du Cinéma ranked The Searchers number 10 in their list of the 100 best films ever made.
In 1989, The Searchers was deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant" by the United States Library of Congress,
and selected for preservation in its National Film Registry; it was one of the first 25 films selected for the registry.
The Searchers was the first major film to have a
purpose-filmed making-of, requested by John Ford.
It deals with most aspects of making the film, including preparation of
the site, construction of props, and filming techniques.
The film explores themes of brother, native american, uncle, racist, prejudice.